JASON HANAFORD

CONTACT

(774) 364-1531 jay.hanaford@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jasonhanaford http://jayhanaford.com

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Lead a small team of graphic designers at Audio Amateur Inc. 6 years.

Created an internship program and several other positions at Audio Amateur Inc.

Head supervisor for the Macintosh computer lab. *Handled all technical issues and management of employees.* 2 years.

President of the Graphic Design Club at Franklin Pierce University. 2 years.

Wrote tutorials for graphic software including Adobe Photoshop and InDesign. Tutorials were open to the public.

AWARDS

Graphic Communications Award of academic excellence and service

High Honors Award in the area of Graphic Communication

Alpha Chi National College Honor Scholarship Society Inductee

Gold Key received at Scholastic Art Awards student art show

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a graphic designer with over 6 years of professional experience. I specialize in web design, print design, corporate identity and branding. I create clean, creative, and functional designs. I am very passionate, organized, and focused with my work.

I am a perfectionist, but I always consider time as an important factor. My experience has given me the ability to easily adapt from being a designer, to coder, to decision maker. My adaptability shows that I can handle any task I'm given whether it be print, branding, multimedia, or web.

SKILLS

HTML, XHTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Abobe Creative Suite 5.5 (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Flash, Fireworks, Acrobat Professional), QuarkXpress, Drupal, Textmate, Firebug, SEO Techniques, Google Analytics, Google AdSense, Email Marketing, Familiar with GitHub, Familiar with Heroku, Amazon S3, Zmag and 3D Issue, Digital Photography, Microsoft Office XP, Microsoft Windows 7, Mac OS X Snow Leopard.

CAREER HISTORY

Graphic Director

Audio Amateur Inc. - May 2005 to present.

Oversee the art direction of the graphics department. Design concepts, identity, execution, and presentation of numerous projects: a monthly subscription-based magazine, two business-to-business periodicals, website design, books, interface design, direct-mail packages, magazine advertisements, web advertisements, product catalogs, and company branding. Some highlights include:

- Design and development of the company website which includes e-commerce and other interactive material.
 Designed with (X)HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- See http://audioamateurinc.com, http://www.audioxpress.com, http://voicecoilmagazine.com
- Created Flash-based digital editions of our magazines for use on the PC, Mac, iPad, and the Android OS.
- Updated the company identity. Modern design concepts were utilized for the overall layout and production of magazines, in-house advertisements, company branding, and websites.
- Saved thousands of dollars per year in production costs by researching alternatives.

Web Designer

Friends of the Israel Defense Forces - Periodic contract job.

Design for implementation of site content throughout. See http://fidf.org

Freelance Graphic Designer

June 2004 to present.

Provide identity, print, and web design for a variety of clients. Select work:

- RyanSobol.com (In Progress) Website design, logo design, site implementation
- The MacDowell Colony Promotional work for a film by Ken Burns and a speech by Ruth Reichl
- Fiveumbrellas Website design for a San Francisco start-up company
- Dear Clowns Promotional work for a documentary film about Patch Adams

EDUCATION

Franklin Pierce University — 2000 to 2004. Bachelor of Arts, Graphic Communications. Minor in Fine Arts. GPA: 3.82. Magna cum Laude.